[indistinct conversations]
[gunshots]
[crowd screaming]
[thud]
[police radio chatter]
[siren wailing]
[door opens]
[sighs]
SO, PATRICK...
THIS DOESN'T LOOK GOOD.
TELL US YOUR SIDE OF THE STORY.
MAYBE WE CAN STRAIGHTEN IT OUT.
IT'S A LONG STORY,
BUT, UH...
THE MAN I SHOT WAS RED JOHN.
SO YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT
YOU DID THAT. YOU KILLED HIM.
YES, I DID.
CAN HARDLY DENY IT, CAN I?
500 WITNESSES.
HE WAS RED JOHN.
RED JOHN, THE FAMOUS
SERIAL KILLER? THAT RED JOHN?
YES. HE KILLED
MY WIFE AND DAUGHTER.
SO WHAT YOU DID, IN YOUR MIND,
IT WAS LIKE A RIGHTEOUS KILL.
YES.
HOW DID YOU KNOW IT WAS HIM?
HE TOLD ME HE WAS.
AND YOU BELIEVED HIM.
HE KNEW THINGS
ABOUT MY WIFE AND DAUGHTER
THAT ONLY RED JOHN
WOULD KNOW.
WHAT WAS THAT?
HOW THEY SMELLED ON THE NIGHT
THAT HE KILLED THEM.
OKAY.
SO DID, UH, DID ANYONE ELSE
HEAR HIM SAY THIS TO YOU?NO.
YOU CAN ONLY ASSERT HE SAID
IT. YOU CAN'T PROVE IT.
NO, I CAN'T, BUT THE GUN HE'S
CARRYING CERTAINLY BACKS ME UP.
AND IF YOU CHECK HIS CELL PHONE,
HE RECEIVED A CALL AT 1:15
FROM AN FBI AGENT
BY THE NAME OF CRAIG O'LAUGHLIN,
WHO IS, WELL, WAS,
A PROVEN ACCOMPLICE OF RED JOHN.
YOU TAKING ANY KIND
OF MEDICATION, PATRICK?
NO.
WHAT'S THAT GOT
TO DO WITH ANYTHING?
HERE'S THE THING.
THAT'S A GREAT STORY YOU TELL.
IF IT WAS TRUE, YOU COULD
PROBABLY ASK FOR MANSLAUGHTER,
TAKE A 5-YEAR HIT, TOPS.
IT IS TRUE.
YEAH.
BUT THE PROBLEM IS, PATRICK,
THE MAN YOU KILLED--
HIS NAME IS TIMOTHY CARTER.
HE'S A WELL-RESPECTED
LOCAL BUSINESSMAN,
A DEVOTED HUSBAND AND FATHER
WITH NO CRIMINAL RECORD.
NO, THAT'S INCORRECT.WAIT A MINUTE.
LET ME FINISH.
WE'VE ALREADY LOOKED
AT HIS CELL PHONE.
I GOT THE DETAILS
RIGHT HERE.
HE LOGGED ZERO CALLS
FROM THIS O'LAUGHLIN--
NONE.
[sighs] AND GUESS WHAT ELSE?
HE DIDN'T HAVE A GUN ON HIM.
NO GUN.
[woman] SO YOU SEE
HOW THIS DOESN'T LOOK GOOD.
LOOKS LIKE EITHER YOU'RE TELLING
US A PACK OF LIES,
OR YOU WENT CRAZY
AND YOU KILLED AN INNOCENT MAN.
♪♪♪
ARDILES.
HEY, I'M GLAD I CAUGHT YOU.
JUST TO SAVE TIME HERE,
I'M SORRY,
BUT I CAN'T CUT YOUR MAN JANE
ANY SLACK ON HIS BAIL.
NO, NO.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO.
NO, ON THE CONTRARY,
I WANT YOU
TO MAKE SURE HE STAYS LOCKED UP
FOR AS LONG AS POSSIBLE.
OKAY. HE'S YOUR MAN.
WELL, DON'T GET ME WRONG--IT'S
HEARTBREAKING TO SEE A GOOD MAN
AND A PRODUCTIVE EMPLOYEE
LIKE JANE GO DOWN IN FLAMES,
BUT THIS IS ABOUT
DAMAGE CONTROL NOW.
NEED TO MAKE SURE
HE IS OUT OF THE WAY
UNTIL THIS MEDIA
CRAPSTORM PASSES.
UNDERSTOOD.
YOUR HONOR,
THE DEFENDANT IS CHARGED
WITH A HEINOUS
AND INEXPLICABLE CRIME
THAT MAY ENTAIL
THE DEATH PENALTY.
HE HAS NO TIES IN THE COMMUNITY,
HE OWNS NO PROPERTY HERE
AND MUST BE CONSIDERED
A VERY SERIOUS FLIGHT RISK.
I ASK THAT BAIL BE SET
AT A MINIMUM OF $1 MILLION.
MR. JANE, ARE YOU SURE
ABOUT REPRESENTING YOURSELF?
IT'S SELDOM A GOOD IDEA.
I AM SURE, YOUR HONOR.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN.
VERY WELL, THEN.
AS TO THE MATTER OF BAIL?
OH, IT'S FINE.
NO--NO OBJECTION.
REALLY? CAN YOU COME UP
WITH A MILLION DOLLARS?
NO. I'M--I'M HAPPY
TO STAY IN JAIL FOR NOW.
I-I NEED A LITTLE TIME
TO THINK ABOUT THINGS.
WELL, THEN,
WE SHALL OBLIGE YOU.
BAIL IS SET
AT A MILLION DOLLARS.
[monitor beeping steadily]
[door opens]
[Bertram] AGENT LISBON.
HOW ARE YOU?
MM. PRETTY GOOD, CONSIDERING.
PAINKILLERS ARE AMAZING
THESE DAYS, HUH?
MM.
HAVE YOU SEEN JANE?
oh, ACROSS A COURTROOM.
HOW WAS HE?
WELL ENOUGH.
I WANT TO EXTEND
MY OWN AND THE BUREAU'S
DEEPEST SYMPATHIES TO YOU.
THANK YOU.
DOCTOR SAYS I SHOULD BE
UP AND AROUND IN A DAY OR SO.
OH, EXCELLENT.
EXCELLENT. BUT...
D-DON'T RUSH YOUR RECOVERY.
YOU HAVE PLENTY OF TIME.
YOU AND YOUR TEAM
ARE SUSPENDED AS OF TODAY.
SUSPENDED.
WHY?
REALLY? YOU HAVE TO ASK?
YOU ALLOWED
A CLEARLY DISTURBED INDIVIDUAL
TO LEAD YOUR ACTIVITIES.
YOU ALLOWED HIM
TO GUN DOWN AN INNOCENT MAN.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
AN INNOCENT MAN.
ON TOP OF WHICH, YOU PERPETRATED
AN ELABORATE DECEPTION ON ME,
IN ORDER TO GATHER EVIDENCE
THAT I, YOUR OWN BOSS,
AM PART OF
A VAST CRIMINAL CONSPIRACY.
SHALL I GO ON?
BUT YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
PLEASE, YOU--
SHH, STAY CALM, LISBON.
FOCUS ON GETTING WELL.
WE'LL REVISIT YOUR STATUS
WHEN YOU'RE FULLY RECOVERED.
BUT WHAT ABOUT JANE?
FORGET ABOUT JANE.
NURSE?
[moans]
[indistinct conversations]
[door buzzes]
SO HOW WAS YOUR WEEK?
[laughs]
OH, YOU SHOULD BE
IN THE HOSPITAL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I'M OKAY.
YOU, ON THE OTHER HAND...
OH, I'M OKAY, TOO.
YOU KILLED AN UNARMED MAN
IN FRONT OF 500 WITNESSES.
YOU'RE NOT OKAY.
HE HAD A GUN.
SOMEONE MUST HAVE TAKEN IT
AND SWITCHED THE CELL PHONE.
IT'S THE ONLY
POSSIBLE EXPLANATION.
THAT, OR YOU WENT NUTS
FOR A MOMENT.
LISBON, LOOK AT ME.
I DIDN'T GO NUTS.
I BELIEVE YOU.
I'M NOT SURE A JURY WILL.
YEAH, WELL,
THAT IS A PROBLEM,
BUT I DID WHAT I HAD TO DO, AND
I'LL LIVE WITH THE CONSEQUENCES.
NEXT TIME YOU COME, CAN YOU
BRING SOME BLUEBERRY MUFFINS?
HEY, GUYS.
GRACE, YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME IN.
WE COULD HAVE GOTTEN
YOUR STUFF.
OH, IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
OKAY.
UM, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
YOU GOOD?
YEAH, I'M FINE.
TWO DAYS AGO YOU SHOT
YOUR FIANCE. YOU CAN'T BE FINE.
JEEZ, CHO.WHAT?
YOU NEED TO SPELL IT OUT?
LOOK, I AM PERFECTLY FINE,
AND I DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT. OKAY?
HEY, BOSS.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO BE HOSPITAL?
NEVER MIND THAT.
BUT YOU SHOULD BE--I'M FINE.
WE NEED TO WORK ON DIGGING
OURSELVES AND JANE OUT OF THIS.
HOW DO WE DO THAT?
FIRST, WE PROVE THAT THIS
TIMOTHY CARTER GUY WAS RED JOHN.
HARD TO DO.
HOW DO WE WORK WITHOUT BADGES?
IT BREAKS THE TERMS
OF OUR SUSPENSION.
YES, BUT I DON'T SEE THAT WE
HAVE ANY OTHER CHOICES. YOU IN?
YES.
GRACE, WHAT AM I THINKING?
YOU NEED TO GO HOME AND REST.
THE GUYS AND I CAN MANAGE THIS
TO START WITH.
SERIOUSLY, I'M TOTALLY OKAY.
NO. YOU NEED TO GO HOME
AND TAKE IT EASY.
I CAN'T GO HOME.
I NEED TO WORK.
I NEED TO BE AROUND PEOPLE.
[clatter, rustle]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I CAN'T TELL YOU WHAT TO DO.
YOU WANT TO STAY, STAY.
WE'D LOVE TO HAVE YOU.
YOU GUYS WANT TO FOCUS ON
FINDING THE GUN AND CELL PHONE?
ASSUME IT WAS TAKEN BEFORE SAC
P.D. AND FORENSICS GOT THERE?
WE NEED TO LOOK
AT THE SECURITY VIDEO.
WHO TOOK THE EVIDENCE
HAS TO BE ON CAMERA.
WE'LL CHECK OUT TIMOTHY CARTER.
IF HE WAS RED JOHN
HE WOULD'VE LEFT
EVIDENCE OF IT SOMEPLACE.
IFHE WAS RED JOHN.
HE WAS.
JANE DID NOT GO CRAZY.
[door slams]
[clanking,
indistinct conversations]
[Rigsby] HI.
REMEMBER US? WERE AT THE
STAKEOUT THAT LED
TO THE SHOOTING?
OH, YEAH. THAT WAS
SOME SITUATION, HUH?
[chuckles]
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
WE NEED TO SEE THAT DAY'S
VIDEO SURVEILLANCE FOOTAGE.
OF COURSE, SURE.
UH, WE GOT IT ON DISK,
OR I CAN DOWNLOAD IT
AND E-MAIL YOU.DISK WOULD BE FINE.
NO PROBLEMO.JUST SHOW ME THE WARRANT.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON IT.WE'LL SEND YOU THE WARRANT.
WE'RE KIND OF IN A HURRY HERE.I BET.
MUST BE ALL KINDS
OF CRAP FLYING OVER THIS.
[chuckles] YOUR GUY REALLY
GOT HIS BRONSON ON, HUH? BOOM.
YEAH.
WILD.
I NEED TO SEE
THE WARRANT FIRST, THOUGH.
IT'S, UH, IT'S PROTOCOL.
THERE IS NO WARRANT.
ASK ME WHY.WHY?
BECAUSE EVERY MEMBER OF OUR UNIT
IS SUSPENDED, BECAUSE OF
THIS KILLING HERE AND TWO OTHER
PEOPLE WE KILLED THIS WEEK.
WOW, THAT'S, UH...
ROUGH WEEK.
[clears throat] UH, I GUESS
I CAN RUN YOU OFF A COPY.
THAT'D BE GREAT.
THANK YOU.
[typing on keyboard]
[bicycle bell jingles]
[car door slams]
[knock on door]
HELLO?
MRS. CARTER? I'M TERESA LISBON.
THIS IS GRACE VAN PELT.
WE'RE COLLEAGUES OF PATRICK JANE
FROM THE CBI.
OH. OH.YES?
WE'D VERY MUCH TO SPEAK WITH YOU
IF THAT'S POSSIBLE.
UM...
YES. ALRIGHT.
PLEASE, COME IN.
THIS IS REVEREND FARLEY
AND MY FRIEND JOAN.
THESE ARE COLLEAGUES
OF PATRICK JANE.
[gasps]JANE?
YES.
I'M NOT SURE
IF THIS IS APPROPRIATE.
NO, THAT'S ALRIGHT.
I'M HAPPY TO TALK WITH THEM.
WELL, IF THAT'S THE CASE,
WE'LL TAKE CHARLAINE
OUT TO PLAY, SHALL WE?
GIVE YOU A MOMENT.
[whispers] THANK YOU.
CAN I OFFER YOU
SOME COFFEE OR TEA?
COFFEE WOULD BE GREAT,
THANK YOU.
THIS MUST BE
A TERRIBLE TIME FOR YOU,
AND I'M SURE YOU HAVE
A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
BUT...
I CAN TELL YOU RIGHT NOW
THAT MY HUSBAND WAS NOT
THIS RED JOHN PERSON.
HE WAS...
THE KINDEST...
GENTLEST SOUL YOU CAN IMAGINE,
AND...
I DON'T KNOW HOW...
BUT YOUR COLLEAGUE MADE
A TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE MISTAKE.
IS IT POSSIBLE YOUR HUSBAND
HID THINGS FROM YOU?
OTHER ASPECTS OF HIS LIFE?
WE WERE VERY CLOSE.
WE DIDN'T KEEP SECRETS
FROM EACH OTHER, EVER.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
EXCUSE ME?
I MEAN, A SECRET,
BY DEFINITION,
IS SOMETHING
YOU DON'T KNOW, RIGHT?
HOW LONG WERE YOU MARRIED?
THREE YEARS THIS FRIDAY.
HE WAS AT THAT MALL,
BUYING AN ANNIVERSARY GIFT.
SO HE WAS THE PERFECT MAN.
NOBODY'S PERFECT.
[voice breaking]
HE IS A GOOD MAN.
WAS.
ONLY LAST MONTH,
HE GOT AN OFFICIAL COMMENDATION
FROM THE SHERIFF.
FOR WHAT?
WHEN DEBBI LUBIN WENT MISSING,
TIM ORGANIZED
THE VOLUNTEER SEARCH PARTIES.
WHO'S DEBBI LUBIN?
OH, UM,
A GIRL FROM OUR CHURCH.
SHE WENT MISSING ABOUT...
[sniffles]
SIX WEEKS AGO. POOR THING.
ONLY 17.
[Van Pelt]
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I DON'T KNOW.
SHE SEEMED SINCERE.
HOUSE IS CLEAN AS A WHISTLE.
HE MUST HAVE KEPT A HIDEOUT
SOMEPLACE ELSE.
[scoffs]
I THINK SHE'S FULL OF IT.
YEAH, YOU MADE THAT PLAIN.
LISTEN, GRACE,
YOU NEED TO SIGN UP FOR YOUR
COUNSELING SESSIONS A.S.A.P.
[scoffs] SESSIONS? WITH
THE SHRINK? I DON'T NEED IT.
WELL, I THINK YOU DO.
BESIDES, IT'S NOT YOUR CALL.
IT'S MANDATORY AFTER A SHOOTING.
THEY SAY A PSYCH COUNSELING
SHEET IN YOUR FILE
DOESN'T MATTER, BUT IT DOES.
GRACE, I'M ASKING YOU
AS A FRIEND. GET HELP.
SEE THE SHRINK.
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
DON'T LET THIS
EAT AWAY AT YOU.
I APPRECIATE THE CONCERN,
REALLY. THANK YOU.
LISTEN, WE'VE GOT
A SERIOUS PROBLEM.
WAS REALLY LOOKING FORWARD
TO A MUFFIN.
TIMOTHY CARTER
LOOKS INNOCENT.
HIS WIFE MAKES A GOOD CASE
FOR HIM. HIS HOUSE WAS CLEAN.
YOU SEARCH THE WHOLE PLACE?
WE DIDN'T RIP OUT
THE FLOORBOARDS.
SURE, HE COULD HAVE
BEEN HIDING SOMETHING,
BUT WITHOUT ANY CLUES,
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO START LOOKING.
WHAT'S CARTER'S STORY?
WHERE'S HE FROM?
ONLY CHILD OF MISSIONARIES,
GREW UP IN AFRICA,
STUDIED AND LIVED ABROAD
UNTIL HE MOVED TO THE U.S.
TO LIVE IN '06.
SO IN OTHER WORDS,
HE JUST APPEARS ON THE GRID
FIVE YEARS AGO. THAT SOUNDS
LIKE A FAKE IDENTITY.
MAYBE. OR HE'S A GUY WHO MOVED
TO THE COUNTRY FIVE YEARS AGO.
THE ONLY RED FLAG WE HAVE
IS THAT HE RECENTLY PUT HIMSELF
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE SEARCH FOR
A GIRL WHO'S GONE MISSING.
THAT'S YOUR CLASSIC
ORGANIZED CRIMINAL
PSYCHOPATH BEHAVIOR--INSERTING
HIMSELF INTO AN INVESTIGATION.
AGAIN, MAYBE. OR HE'S A GOOD GUY
WHO WANTS TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
WE HAVE NO HARD FACTS,
JUST YOUR WORD.
AND YOU'RE BEGINNING TO THINK
THAT MAYBE MY WORD IS DUBIOUS.
MAYBE I'M CRAZY.
MAYBE I SHOT SOME RANDOM GUY.
NO.
IT'S CROSSED MY MIND, YEAH.
FAIR ENOUGH.
GUESS I'M GONNA HAVE TO GET OUT
TO HELP YOU WITH THIS.
HOW? YOUR BAIL'S SET
AT A MILLION BUCKS.YEAH, THAT'S NO PROBLEM.
ONCE I GET THE MONEY,
I'LL CALL YOU.HOW YOU GONNA DO THAT?
I'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
MEANTIME, I NEED YOU
TO GET AHOLD
OF TIMOTHY CARTER'S
PERSONAL EFFECTS FROM FORENSICS.
HOW AM I GONNA DO THAT?
YOU'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
[screaming]
JANE SAYS THE GUN
WAS IN THE NEWSPAPER.
[keys tap]
[Cho] THERE.
LOOKS LIKE A WAITRESS.
CAN'T SEE
IF SHE TAKES ANYTHING.
[keys tap]
SECURITY GUARD.
[tap]
[Rigsby]
AND THAT'S THE FORENSIC TECH.
NO GUN.
ONE OF THOSE THREE
MUST'VE TAKEN IT--
WAITRESS, SECURITY GUARD,
FORENSIC TECH.
YEAH, IF THERE WASA GUN.
[Rigsby] YEAH.
[indistinct conversations]
[man speaking indistinctly over P.A.]
I LOVE A GOOD GAME OF CARDS.
WHAT'S THE BUY-IN?
BUY-IN'S 100 GRAND,
OUTSIDE MONEY.
EXCELLENT. I'M IN.
YOU GOT TO HAVE COLLATERAL,
SO WE KNOW
YOU CAN COVER YOUR DEBTS.
NO PROBLEM.
I GOT ALL SORTS OF COLLATERAL.
I HAVE A VINTAGE CAR COLLECTION
WORTH 2 1/2 MIL OR THEREABOUTS.
HOW DO WE KNOW THAT?
WELL, WHAT KIND OF FOOL
WOULD LIE TO FOLKS LIKE YOU
ABOUT SOMETHIN' LIKE THAT?
IF YOU FOUND OUT I WAS LYING,
YOU'D KILL ME, RIGHT?
TRUE. TAKE A SEAT.
THANK YOU.
[clears throat]
I WAS THE FIRST TECH
ON SCENE.
SPOKE TO THE DETECTIVES
FROM SAC P.D.YOU KNOW.
THERE'S MULTIPLE INVESTIGATIONS
GOING ON HERE.
OH, SURE. BUT AREN'T
YOU GUYS SUSPENDED?
TECHNICALLY, YEAH,
BUT WE'RE JUST TALKING HERE.
I'M NOT SURE I SHOULD BE...
TALKING TO YOU.
WHY NOT? YOU HAVE
SOMETHING TO HIDE?
NO. WHAT WOULD I BE HIDING?
LOOK.
SOMEONE TOOK A CELL PHONE
AND A GUN FROM THE CRIME SCENE.
NOT ME. THERE WAS NO GUN,
NOT THAT I SAW.
WAIT.
LOOK ME IN THE EYE
AND TELL ME THAT.
THERE WAS NO GUN.
[indistinct conversations]
25.
[whistles]
OKAY, WELL, I'M GONNA SEE YOU,
AND THEN I WILL RAISE YOU...
ALL IN.
[clears throat]
YOU KNOW, PUSS...
WHEN YOU BLUFF,
YOU HAVE A REAL OBVIOUS TELL.
WHEN I REACH TO TUG ON MY EAR,
BUT STOP MYSELF?
YEAH.
OH. OHH, BAM. STRAIGHT FLUSH.
HE GOT YOU GOOD.
[laughs]
[snorts]
[tires screech]
TERESA LISBON?
YES?
PHIL SAYS TO TELL YOUR FRIEND HE
DOESN'T WANT TO SEE HIM AGAIN.
HI.
HEY.
SO WHAT DID YOU DO,
HONESTLY?
HE HAD A GUN.
NO, I MEAN, HOW DID YOU
RAISE THE BAIL MONEY?
OH, THAT.
UH, MURDER FOR HIRE.
KILLED A SNITCH.
STABBED HIM IN THE KIDNEYS.
YOU DID NOT.
I DID NOT.
I WON IT IN A CARD GAME,
BUT I HAD YOU FOR A MOMENT.
YOU REALLY DO
FEAR FOR MY SANITY.
NO. WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WELL, FIRST, EGGS.
THEN WE GO SEE SALLY CARTER.
DID YOU GET HER HUSBAND'S
EFFECTS FROM FORENSICS?
YES. I HAD TO LIE
THROUGH MY TEETH,
CALL IN ALL KINDS OF FAVORS,
AND IT WAS A BUST.
NOTHING USEFUL.
WATCH, KEY, GUM, WEDDING RING.
DOESN'T MATTER. GETS US
IN THE ROOM WITH SALLY CARTER.
I DON'T THINK SHE'S GONNA
WANNA TALK TO YOU.
REALLY?
YOU KILLED HER HUSBAND.
WELL, THERE YOU GO.
THE ICE IS BROKEN.
WE HAVE SOMETHING
TO TALK ABOUT.
NO, HE DIDN'T HAVE A GUN,
NOT THAT I SAW.
DID YOU NOTICE THE NEWSPAPER
THAT HE WAS CARRYING?
NO. I DIDN'T REALLY
SEE ANYTHING.
I WAS TRYING TO
COMFORT HIM THE BEST I COULD.
SO HE WAS STILL ALIVE.
YES.DID HE SAY ANYTHING?
HE SAID, "GIVE MY LOVE
TO SALLY AND CHARLAINE."
THAT'S ALL?
THEN HE DIED.
I THINK, ANYHOW.
HE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING ELSE,
AND THE SECURITY GUARD
WAS FREAKING OUT AT ME,
SO I LEFT HIM.
WHY WAS THE GUARD
FREAKING OUT?
HE WAS LIKE,
"GET AWAY FROM THE BODY!
THIS IS EVIDENCE!
DON'T TOUCH HIM!"
HE WAS KIND OF
A JERK ABOUT IT.
THIS GUARD--
HE WAS A YOUNGISH BALD GUY?
YES, WITH CRAZY EYES.
[man] YEAH, RON DEUTSCH.
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO BE WORKING
TODAY, BUT HE DIDN'T SHOW UP.
I NEED HIS HOME ADDRESS.
[sighs]
[types on keyboard]
[doorbell rings]
I HAVE A BAD FEELING
ABOUT THIS.
WELL, YOU'VE BEEN SHOT. YOU'RE
BOUND TO HAVE A GLOOMY OUTLOOK.
IGNORE YOUR FEELINGS.
I'M SORRY, AGENTS.
THIS ISN'T A GOOD TIME.
WE'RE HAVING
A SMALL MEMORIAL PARTY FOR TIM.
WE HAVE
HIS PERSONAL EFFECTS HERE.
THANK YOU.
I CAN TAKE THOSE.
I'M SORRY. MRS. CARTER HAS TO
SIGN FOR THEM IN OUR PRESENCE.
SHOULDN'T TAKE LONG.
I SEE. UH, LET'S GO AROUND
TO THE KITCHEN DOOR.
OKAY, THEN.
GOT TO GO.
[cell phone shuts]
[indistinct conversations]
WELL, THIS IS EASY AS PIE.
SO FAR.
PIE.
[door opens]
OH. BUT YOU'RE--
[door closes]YES, I AM.
SALLY, YOU ALRIGHT?
THIS...
THIS IS PATRICK JANE,
THE MAN WHO SHOT TIM.
[whispers] OH, MY LORD.
DON'T BE SCARED.
I'M HARMLESS, TRULY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I HAD TO TALK TO YOU
FACE-TO-FACE,
SO I'D KNOW FOR SURE.
IF YOUR HUSBAND'S INNOCENT,
IF I MADE A MISTAKE,
THEN I'M TRULY, DEEPLY SORRY,
AND I SWEAR TO YOU,
I WILL SPEND THE REST OF MY LIFE
EARNING YOUR FORGIVENESS.
MR. JANE...
AS GOD IS MY WITNESS,
MY HUSBAND NEVER
BROKE THE LAW IN HIS LIFE.
YOU MURDERED A GOOD MAN.
DO YOU HAVE ANY TEA?
[knocks on door]
MR. DEUTSCH!
OPEN IT UP.
YOU GOT A WARRANT?
WE DON'T NEED ONE. WE JUST
WANT A QUICK LOOK AROUND.
LET ME CHECK WITH MY BOSS.
SIR...
WON'T BE LONG.
YOU HEAR THAT?WHAT?
SOUND OF A STRUGGLE, COMING
FROM INSIDE THE APARTMENT.
OH, YEAH. I DO.
SOMEONE MIGHT BE IN DANGER.
YEAH. [grunts]
[Rigsby] HEY. SECURITY GUARD'S
DEAD. HAIR DRYER IN THE BATHTUB.
COULD IT BE AN ACCIDENT?
Well, it could be.
EXCEPT THE DEAD GUY'S BALD,
NEAR ENOUGH,
SO WHAT WOULD HE USE
A HAIR DRYER FOR?
LOOKS LIKE SUICIDE OR MURDER.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
NOT FOR MR. DEUTSCH,
GOD REST HIM,
BUT SUPPORTS JANE'S STORY.
Yeah.
SOMEONE MUST'VE ARRANGED
FOR DEUTSCH TO TAKE THE GUN,
SWITCH THE PHONE,
KILLED HIM TO KEEP HIM QUIET.
Be sure that forensics
SEARCH DEUTSCH'S
APARTMENT CAREFULLY.
IT'S A LONG SHOT,
BUT WE MAY GET LUCKY
AND FIND THE GUN OR THE PHONE.
IT'S WEIRD HOW MUCH WE HAD
IN COMMON RIGHT FROM THE START.
WE JUST NATURALLY
MADE A COUPLE.
SOUL MATES.
YES. SOUL MATES.
[knocks]JANE.
OH. [whispers]
EXCUSE ME, PLEASE, SALLY.
[lowered voice] THE FIRST
SECURITY GUARD ON THE SCENE
AFTER THE SHOOTING, IS DEAD--
HAIR-DRYER-IN-THE-BATHTUB DEAD.
WELL, THAT'S A RELIEF.
I MEAN...
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
THIS WOMAN IS GOOD.
STARTING TO DOUBT MY OWN STORY.
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
[clears throat]
[sips] MM.
SALLY, WOULD YOU MIND
IF I USED YOUR BATHROOM?
NOT AT ALL.THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THAT'S ALL WE NEED.
WE'LL LEAVE YOU IN PEACE.
UH, IN JUST ONE MOMENT.
SEE, THING IS, SALLY,
I LIKE YOU.
I CAN TELL THAT YOU'RE
A GOOD, HONEST PERSON,
WHICH MEANS EITHER I'M CRAZY
OR YOUR HUSBAND WAS KEEPING
SOME VERY DARK SECRETS FROM YOU,
AND I-I'M PRETTY SURE
I'M NOT CRAZY.
MY HUSBAND KEPT
NO SECRETS FROM ME. NONE.
ALL MEN KEEP SECRETS
FROM THEIR WIVES--ALL OF THEM.
TIM WAS NO DIFFERENT.
YOU'RE WRONG.
I BET I CAN PROVE I'M RIGHT.
YOU RECOGNIZE THESE?
YES, OF COURSE--
TIM'S KEY RING.
DO YOU HAVE
YOUR OWN KEYS CLOSE BY?
HOW MANY KEYS
DO YOU HAVE THERE?
UH, SIX.
YOU SURE?
SIX KEYS.
HUH.
YOUR HUSBAND HAS SEVEN.
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR,
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN.
WHAT'S THE SEVENTH KEY FOR?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T FIND THAT ODD?
NO. I'M SURE LOTS
OF HUSBANDS AND WIVES
HAVE A DIFFERENT
NUMBER OF KEYS.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYING.
EVERYBODY HAS SECRETS.
THIS IS PROOF POSITIVE THAT
YOUR HUSBAND WAS NO DIFFERENT.
I WONDER WHAT IT OPENS.
YOU THINK YOU'RE SO SMART
WITH THESE LITTLE
MIND GAMES, DON'T YOU?
IT'S JUST A QUESTION.
BUT THE TRUTH IS...
YOU ARE NOTHING BUT A SAD,
CRAZY PERSON, AND A MURDERER.
AND I'M SORRY,
BUT I WANT YOU TO LEAVE
MY HOUSE RIGHT THIS MINUTE.
OKAY.
I DON'T GET WHAT YOU THOUGHT
WAS GONNA HAPPEN.
I WAS FEELING MY WAY.
[sighs] WHAT NOW?
WELL, JUST DRIVE
AROUND THE BLOCK.
OKAY.
WHY?
QUESTION...
DO YOU TRUST ME?
NOT 100%, NO.
DIFFERENT QUESTION, THEN.
OH. COULD YOU STOP RIGHT HERE?
[seat belt clicks][sighs]
[groans][car alert beeps]
SO WHAT'S THE QUESTION?[groans]
HOW'S YOUR INJURY?
IT HURTS.
MM. YOU THINK YOU CAN RUN?NO.
YEAH. PROBABLY DON'T
WANT TO GET TOO EXCITED.
YOU'LL POP YOUR STITCHES.WHAT?
I'M GONNA SNEAK
INSIDE THE CARTER HOUSE.
STAY HERE
UNTIL I CALL YOU.DON'T--
DON'T YOU DARE--JANE?
JANE!
[sighs]
[thud]
[indistinct conversations]
[Sally]
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
GOODNIGHT.
[Joan] GOODNIGHT.
IF YOU NEED ME TO STAY OVER,
KEEP YOU COMPANY...
I CAN BABYSIT CHARLAINE.
I'LL BE FINE.
ANYTHING YOU NEED.
THANK YOU, HONEY.
YOU'VE BEEN A ROCK.
[kiss]
CALL ME, OKAY?I WILL.
ALRIGHT. GOODNIGHT.
[creak]
[door closes]
[footsteps approach]
[keys jangle]
[switch clicks]
HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO SAY IT?
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
DON'T YOU EVER LOOK AT ME.
[sighs]
[drawer closes]
YOU KNOW, DON'T YOU?
YOU KNOW.
[whispers]
WHAT DOES THIS OPEN?
[sniffles]
SHH. OH, DEBBI.
OPEN YOUR EYES.
LOOK AT IT.
WHAT DOES THIS OPEN?
[voice breaking]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU LYING SLUT![slap]
YOU AND TIM HAVE BEEN KEEPING
SECRETS FROM ME ALL ALONG,
HAVEN'T YOU? ALL ALONG!
WHAT DOES THIS OPEN?!
IT OPENS MY LOCKER
AT THE CBI GYM.
GOOD NEWS IS, YOUR HUSBAND
WASN'T HIDING ANYTHING FROM YOU.
YOU REALLY WERE SOUL MATES.
BAD NEWS?
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST,
YOU LOONY BITCH.
[Lisbon] OH, MY GOD.
ON YOUR KNEES.
PUT YOUR HANDS ON YOUR HEAD.
[keys clatter]
LISTEN, THIS GIRL IN
THE BASEMENT CHANGES THE GAME.
WE CAN'T APPEAR VINDICTIVE.
JANE HAS AN ENORMOUS AMOUNT
OF PUBLIC SYMPATHY RIGHT NOW.
YEAH, WELL, THE D.A. IS TELLING
ME TO GO FULL SPEED AT HIM.
VIGILANTE JUSTICE
CAN'T GO UNPUNISHED,
REGARDLESS WHAT THE SYMPATHETIC
CIRCUMSTANCES MIGHT BE.
OH, NO, ABSOLUTELY.
A FIRM LINE DRAWN UNDER THIS
EPISODE IS BEST FOR THE BUREAU.
IT WAS BEST FOR ALL CONCERNED.
I'M JUST SAYING...
NO DEATH PENALTY, RIGHT?
NO, THAT'S OUT NOW,
BUT WE ARE CONFIDENT
FIRST DEGREE MURDER
WILL STAND UP.
FACTS DON'T ALLOW
FOR ANY OTHER VERDICT.
AFTER A WHILE,
I STOPPED TRYING TO ESCAPE.
THEN I THOUGHT
ABOUT KILLING MYSELF.
BUT THEN I THOUGHT ABOUT
MY MOM AND DAD AND MY BROTHER,
AND I COULDN'T DO IT.
I HAD TO STAY ALIVE FOR THEM,
SO THAT KEPT A SPARK OF HOPE
ALIVE INSIDE ME.
AND THEN, JUST WHEN
I WAS ABOUT TO DESPAIR,
MR. JANE AND AGENT LISBON
CAME AND RESCUED ME.
YOU'RE A BRAVE GIRL, DEBBI.
NOW THAT YOU'VE HAD TIME
TO LOOK BACK CALMLY,
WHAT IS YOUR OPINION
OF TIMOTHY CARTER?
HE'S A MONSTER.
THANK YOU.
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS.
THANK YOU,MR. JANE.
MR. ARDILES?
DEBBI, JUST ONE QUESTION.
DID TIMOTHY CARTER EVER SAY
TO YOU THAT HE WAS RED JOHN?
NO, SIR.
DID HE EVER MENTION
THE NAME RED JOHN?
NO, SIR.
DID HE EVER MENTION ANY OTHER
CRIMES HE MIGHT HAVE COMMITTED?
NO, BUT I DON'T SEE HOW THAT--THANK YOU SO MUCH, DEBBI.
YOU'VE BEEN SUPER HELPFUL.
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS,
YOUR HONOR.
REDIRECT, MR. JANE?
[mouths word]
THE WITNESS MAY STEP DOWN.
THANK YOU, DEBBI.
MR. ARDILES?
NOW MR. JANE
IS GOING TO STAND UP HERE
IN A MOMENT,
AND HE'S GOING TO TELL YOU
THAT TIMOTHY CARTER
WAS RED JOHN.
THE FACT IS, HE HAS NO PROOF
OF THAT--NONE WHATSOEVER.
NOW WAS, UH, WAS TIM CARTER
A NICE MAN? NO.
OBVIOUSLY NOT.
BUT WAS HE A SERIAL KILLER?
DO WE HAVE ANY PROOF
THAT HE EVER KILLED ANYONE?
ANYONE AT ALL? NO. WE DON'T.
THE ONLY MURDER THAT WE KNOW OF,
THE ONLY MURDER
THAT IS AN ATTESTED FACT,
IS THE MURDER COMMITTED
BY THIS MAN HERE, PATRICK JANE--
A MURDER COMMITTED
OUT OF MISGUIDED LUST
FOR PERSONAL VENGEANCE.
PROSECUTOR SAYS THAT
TIMOTHY CARTER WASN'T RED JOHN.
WELL, CARTER TOLD ME HIMSELF
THAT HE WASRED JOHN,
BUT I-I CAN'T PROVE THAT.
THE FORENSIC EVIDENCE
IS INCONCLUSIVE.
HIS WIFE REFUSES
TO TALK TO ANYONE,
REFUSES TO SPEAK AT ALL,
SO SHE'S NO USE TO US.
WHAT ABOUT CARTER'S RECORDS?
SURELY THERE MUST BE
SOME CLUES THERE--NO.
ON PAPER,
THIS MAN SEEMS TO APPEAR
OUT OF NOWHERE FIVE YEARS AGO.
BEFORE THAT, NOTHING.
WHY?
BECAUSE TIMOTHY CARTER
IS AN INVENTED IDENTITY, A MASK.
I'M NOT GUILTY
OF KILLING TIMOTHY CARTER
BECAUSE TIMOTHY CARTER
NEVER EXISTED.
THERE IS NO TIMOTHY CARTER.
THERE IS ONLY RED JOHN.
RED JOHN...
STARTED KILLING PEOPLE
12 YEARS AGO.
IT'S HARD TO PUT AN EXACT NUMBER
ON HOW MANY PEOPLE HE'S KILLED,
BUT IT'S SOMEWHERE AROUND 28--
NEARLY ALL WOMEN,
LATE AT NIGHT, IN THEIR HOMES.
HE WAKES THEM FIRST,
BECAUSE HE LIKES TO SEE
THE FEAR IN THEIR EYES.
HE LIKES TO HEAR THEM BEG
FOR MERCY AS HE CUTS THEM OPEN.
HE DID THAT
TO MY WIFE AND DAUGHTER...
AND I'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR HIM EVER SINCE...
LOOKING FOR PERSONAL VENGEANCE.
I BELIEVE THAT'S... MY RIGHT.
I HAVE THE RIGHT TO KILL THE MAN
THAT KILLED MY FAMILY.
I DON'T SAY I SHOULDN'T BE
PUNISHED FOR DOING WHAT I DID.
I FEEL I HAD NO CHOICE.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
[Van Pelt] ANY NEWS?
THE JURY'S OUT.
HOW'S IT LOOKING?
MAYBE IF WE'RE LUCKY, HE'LL
GIVE HIM SECOND-DEGREE MURDER.
JANE WILL BE OUT OF PRISON
IN THREE OR FOUR YEARS.
[buzzer]
THE JURY'S BACK ALREADY.
THAT CAN'T BE GOOD.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
OF THE JURY,
HAVE YOU REACHED
A UNANIMOUS VERDICT?
WE HAVE, YOUR HONOR.
PLEASE STATE YOUR VERDICT
FOR THE COURTROOM.
WE, THE JURY, FIND
THE DEFENDANT, PATRICK JANE...
NOT GUILTY, ON ALL COUNTS.
[gallery murmuring]
[gavel bangs]
QUIET!
[murmuring continues]
SO... WHAT NOW?
NOW?
WELL,
TEA WOULD HIT THE SPOT.
NO. I MEAN, WHAT NOW?
WELL, YOU'VE DONE WHAT
YOU SET OUT TO DO.
YOU GOT YOUR VENGEANCE.
DO YOU FEEL DIFFERENT?
FEEL BETTER?
NO. I FEEL GUILTY.
GUILTY? WHY?
FOR DECEIVING THE JURY.
I MEAN, I HAD NO CHOICE.
GOING TO PRISON FOR MURDER
WOULD HAVE BEEN
A VICTORY FOR RED JOHN.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
RED JOHN'S DEAD.
TIMOTHY CARTER'S DEAD.
HE WAS AN EVIL MAN,
BUT HE WASN'T RED JOHN.
RED JOHN...
IS STILL ALIVE.
WATCH THE ROAD.